Hi everyone and welcome.
Let's start building our reading skills.
And here comes the very first lesson.
I know that all of us can't wait
to take the exam right away and make
ourselves familiar with frequently asked questions in it.
However, it won't be useful unless our reading skills are improved.
And this is also the very first goal
that we need to achieve to master IELTS Reading.
I want to start the lesson with a
small challenge for you guys.
On the next screen, there will be a picture.
You have 10 seconds to look at it
and then answer some of my questions related to the picture.
Are you ready?
10 seconds starts now.
Okay, now let's answer my questions.
Number one, how many people are there in the picture?
Looking at the picture quickly, you can see
that there are three people, a man, a woman and a boy.
They look like a happy family, don't they?
Let's continue.
Number two, is the car running?
No, obviously the car stays still and even
the trunk is still open.
We will answer one more question.
Number three, what's the mother doing?
She's holding her son's hand.
Good job, everyone.
Let's continue.
Now let's answer some more questions still about that picture.
Number one, how many trees are there in the picture?
Which brand of shoes is the woman wearing?
Number three, what is the type of the
house in the background?
I'm pretty sure that if you don't look
at the photo again, many of you can't
answer these three questions.
Even if you look back at it, I'm
not sure you can answer them.
Just kidding.
You don't need to do that again to
find the answer.
So why can you answer the first three
questions easily, but you can't do the same
thing with the three latter ones?
Because the first three sentences show the main
information of the picture.
They tell us what the picture is about.
In reading, these are called keywords, which are
really important pieces of information, helping us to
understand the content of a sentence, a paragraph,
or a reading passage.
The three latter questions are difficult to answer
because those are small details or minor details.
They do not affect the overall meaning.
We can ignore them and still understand the main content.
When you read anything not only for IELTS Reading,
identifying and focusing on keywords,
ignoring minor details are necessary.
They help you to speed up the reading
process and get a lot of information in
a short period of time.
Our first lesson aims to help you.
Number one, remember and understand the definition of keywords.
Number two, understand different types of keywords.
And number three, apply the knowledge of keywords
to the reading passage through three parts of the lesson.
Number one: Definition of keywords.
Number two: Types of keywords
And number three: Practice identifying keywords
in sentences and paragraphs.
Once you apply these core knowledge to IELTS Reading,
you will find it much easier.
So stay with me.
All right, let's get started.
Keywords are words in a sentence, a passage,
a text, and carry the main content that
the writer wants to convey.
These words often have important meaning or serve
the purpose of placing emphasis based on the
writer's intention.
In other words, we just need to look at these words.
We still understand what the sentence is about.
That's right.
Keywords help us narrow down the amount of
information we need to read and process questions
more quickly.
Human brains can only effectively process a certain
amount of information at a time.
Obviously, selecting what to read will make us
increase our reading speed, remember the information better,
and be more focused compared to reading all
the words in a sentence, a paragraph, or a text.
Now we've understood the definition, we're going to
learn about different types of keywords so that
we can use them effectively.
Let's go.
To begin with, I would like to give
you the following pictures.
Please guess what I'm trying to talk about.
One thing in common between these pictures, as
you've already seen, is that they are cars.
To be more specific, we are talking about
different types of cars.
In the next screen, please pause the video
and spend two minutes studying the highlighted keywords
in two colors in order to see the
differences between them.
Once you have your own answers, we'll get
back to our lesson.
See you in a bit.
I guess most of you notice that the
yellow keywords are proper nouns or acronyms, don't you?
And the blue keywords are general words.
In general, the yellow keywords are called unchangeable keywords
or keywords that cannot be changed.
Sounds reasonable, right?
Since it's a personal name, we cannot change anything.
The blue keywords are changeable keywords
or the keywords that can be changed.
In this example, types can be replaced by kinds.
They both refer to a particular group of something.
Big can be replaced to large.
Good can be replaced with suitable.
Trips can be replaced with journeys.
They have the same meaning.
In this context, taken off is used when
we are talking about a car with a
removable roof.
So, we can replace it with removed.
Very can be replaced with extremely.
Fun can be replaced with exciting.
And the phrase run on means using electricity to run.
Instead, we can change it to the word use.
Let's get more specific about each type, shall we?
Starting with changeable keywords.
We're going to look at all the changeable
keywords we just saw in the last example
one more time.
Now, I'd like you to name the part
of speech of those keywords and divide them
into four groups for me.
Let's spend about one minute doing this exercise.
Make it fast, everyone.
Three, two, one, start.
These keywords are divided into four groups corresponding
to four parts of speech.
Nouns.
Types.
Trips.
Verbs.
Taken off.
Run on.
Adjectives.
Big.
Good.
Fun.
Adverbs.
Very.
That's right.
When we read a sentence, nouns, verbs, adjectives,
adverbs are the words we need to focus
on because they will often be the keywords
expressing the main content of the sentence.
There are other parts of speech like pronouns,
prepositions, or articles.
We can skip them and still understand the meaning.
Now, let's come to unchangeable keywords or keywords
that cannot be changed.
There are three common types of unchangeable keywords
including proper nouns.
The main feature of these words is to
capitalize the first letters.
Names of people, places, companies, and brands are
often in this group and these keywords are
really easy to find because of their capital letters.
In our example, there are the names of two cars.
Kia Sorento and Mercedes-Benz GT.
Acronyms.
Acronyms like the word SUV in the paragraph
introducing the cars.
This is an acronym for Sport Utility Vehicle
or our word IELTS.
It's also an acronym.
The full phrase is International English Language Testing System.
Well, it is just hard to remember,
so you just have to say IELTS.
But remember to pronounce it right.
Do not pronounce it like IELT.
While the nouns we only capitalize the first
letters, with acronyms we usually capitalize all the
letters which make them easier to identify.
This is also a type of keyword we
need to pay attention to.
Numbers.
Numbers are often categorized as unchangeable keywords due
to their nature of expressing specific quantities which
are rarely changed.
We can find metrics, time, and currencies in this group.
For example, there are about 26 types of cars available.
No kidding, that's a lot.
Until now, the knowledge is quite enough so
let's practice.
Here we go.
Let's start with something simple.
In the first exercise, your task is very simple.
I have some keywords available for you here.
Within 30 seconds, please divide them into two groups.
Changeable keywords and unchangeable keywords.
That's all.
Are you ready?
In three, two, one, go.
Here's the key.
Let's check together.
This exercise is just a warm-up activity.
It has nothing challenging at all.
Now we're going to make it a bit more difficult.
I'll give you some sentences.
Please identify the keywords in each sentence and
categorize them.
You are going to pause the video on
the next screen to do this task within
one minute and then we'll check the answers together.
Let's do it everyone.
All right, here's the key.
If there is any new vocab, remember to
write them down in your notebook.
Let's finish with the most challenging task.
Now, I'll give you a passage.
Help me point out the keywords and categorize them.
Let's spend about five minutes doing this.
Pause the video so that you can do
it carefully and then check the answer.
Here's the answer.
Let's check together.
After this exercise, you will probably wonder why
all nouns, verbs, adjectives and adverbs are not
highlighted as keywords.
I'm going to give you two tips on
identifying keywords so that you can narrow down
the amount of information you have to read
and increase your reading speed.
The words which are mentioned several times only
need to be identified once.
For example, in the last reading,
two words "brands" and "cars" appear continuously,
so identifying them in the first sentence is enough.
We can skip them in the remaining sentences.
Words with general meanings used for many contexts
can be omitted, even though they belong to
the noun, verb, adjective or adverb group.
For example, to be, have, include, they're, and people, etc.
By that, we can leave out more information that needs attention.
Please note them down so you can practice more.
Well done, everyone!
We've completed the first skill building lesson of
the Reading 4.0 - 5.0 course, which focuses
on identifying keywords,
categorizing changeable keywords and unchangeable keywords.
Also, we've achieved three goals.
The first is remember and understand the definition of keywords.
The second, understand different types of keywords.
And the third, apply the knowledge of keywords
to the reading passage.
See you all in the next lesson.
I'm Teacher Francois.
Goodbye.